اَعُوْذُ بِاللهِ مِنَّ الشِّيْطَانِ الرَّجِيْمِ
بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمَانِ الرَّحِيْمَ
اَلْحَمْدُ لله رَبِّ الّعَالَمِيْن، وَالصَّلَاةُ وَالسَّلَامُ عَلى سَيِّدِنَا محمد وَعَلَى اَلِهِ وَصَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تَسْلِيْمًا كَثِيْرا
السلام عليكم ورحمةالله
We ask Allahعَزّوجَلّ to bless this gathering and we ask Allahعَزّوجَلّ to make it beneficial for all of us,
نَسْعَلُ الله عزوجل اَنْ يَرْزُقْنَا الْجَنَّةْ وَنَعُوْذُبِهِ مِنَّ النَّار
رَبَّنَا آتِنَا فِي الدُّنْيَا حَسَنَةً وَفِي الْآخِرَةِ حَسَنَةً وَقِنَا عَذَابَ النَّارِ
صلى الله على سيدنا محمد وعلى آله وصحبه وسلم
For the past few weeks, preparing for this series of talks on Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه.
I got to do some reading about Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه.
Now, we all know that Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) is the greatest, after the Anbiyaa(انبياء) of Allahعَزّوجَلّ.
But somehow we always have this, special love of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab رضي الله عنه,
everybody is impressed with him.
With the personality of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب), the power and strength of Al-Farooque(الفاروق).
So, sometimes we don't do a lot of studying on the Siddique رضي الله عنه.
So, in the past weeks I had a chance to be, exposed in detail to his personality.
And Subhaan Allah(سبحان الله), his personality is amazing, surprising.
Because whenever you pull out a list of a good deed, you would find the name of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) on the top.
Whichever list, you pull out, you're going to find his name on there and it's the first name.
He was the first Muslim,
he was the first Khalifah(خليفه),
he was the first and only person to be with Rasool Allah ﷺ on Al-Hijrah(ألهجرة).
He was the first on Eeman(ايمان),
Rasool Allah ﷺ says, that the Eeman(ايمان) of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) is greater than all of the Ummah(أمة).
Even on issues that we would regard as normal deeds.
Rasool Allah ﷺ was once sitting in the Masjid(مسجد) and he asked the Sahabah(صحابه),
who's fasting this day?
Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) said: I am!
Who has visited an ill person.?
Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) said: I did!
Who has followed a Janazah(جنازه).?
Who on this day, has given out Sadaqah(صدقه).?
Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) said: I did!
And everybody else in the Masjid(مسجد) is looking around and the only hand that is going up is the hand of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
In fact, in another narration of this.
It says that this happened after Salat-Ul-Fajr(صلاة الفجر)
because Rasool Allah ﷺ used to meet with the Sahabah(صحابه),
after Salat-Ul-Fajr(صلاة الفجر) and talk with them in the Masjid(مسجد), after Salah(صلاة), they would talk.
For example, they would talk about dreams,
they would talk about different issues.
Rasool Allah ﷺ would spend time with the Sahabah(صحابه) after Salat-Ul-Fajr(صلاة الفجر), conversing with them.
So it says, Rasool Allah ﷺ asked, Who has followed the Janazah(جنازه).?
So Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) said: We just started our day!
And then he said: Who has given Sadaqah(صدقه).?
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب), We just started our day!
But Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه said:
When I was coming to the Masjid(مسجد), I saw a poor man outside, so I gave him Sadaqah(صدقه).
So who has visited an ill person.?
Umar(عمر) said: We just started our day.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابو بكر الصديق) said: I heard that Abdur Rahman Ibn Auf(عبدالرحمن ابن عوف) was ill,
so before I came to the Masjid(مسجد), I went to visit him.
So whenever Rasool Allah ﷺ would ask a question, it's Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) who would say: I did it.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: If these deeds combined together in one person, that person is going to Jannah(جنة).
So again, whatever list you look at, you would find Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) on the top of it.
Ali Bin Abi Talib رضي الله عنه says,
هُوَ سَبَّاقْ
He was the first.
And whenever we would compete with him on any deed, he would come ahead of us.
And that's a statement made by Ali Bin Abi Talib رضي الله عنه.
And we know the story
when Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) wanted to compete with Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه
and keep in mind
that competition in good, is good.
Competition in good deeds, is a good deed.
See in Islam, we're not supposed to compete on worldly affairs,
we're not supposed to compete on Duniyah(دنيا)
when it comes to Duniyah(دنيا), Rasool Allah ﷺ says,
فَاتَّقُو الله وَاَجْمِلُوْا فِي الطَّلَبْ
Have Taqwa(تقوى) of Allah, and take it easy when it comes to Duniyah(دنيا).
نَفْسًا رُوح الْقُدُس فِي رَوعِيْ اَنَّه’ لَنْ تَمُوتَ نَفْسٌ
حَتَّى تَقْضِي اَجَلَهَا وَتَسْتَوْفِيَ رِزْقَهَا  فَاتَّقُوا اللهَ ، وَأَجْمِلُوا فِي الطَّلَبِ
Rasool Allah ﷺ says: The Holy Spirit, Jibreel عليه السّلام has inspired to me
that no one would die until they reach the end of their life, their prescribed life,
and until they get all of their provisions.
So, take it easy in Duniyah(دنيا).
فَاتَّقُوا اللهَ ، وَأَجْمِلُوا فِي الطَّلَبِ
So look at Duniyah(دنيا), Rasool Allah ﷺ says, Calm down, take it easy.
But look at the terminology that was used with Aakhirah(آخرة).
In Qur'an Allah سبحانه تعالى says:
سَابِقُوا إِلَىٰ وَجَنَّةٍ
وَسَارِعُوا إِلَىٰ  وَجَنَّةٍ
كَانُوا يُسَارِعُونَ فِي الْخَيْرَاتِ وَيَدْعُونَنَا رَغَبًا وَرَهَبًا
The words used, when it comes to Aakhirah(آخرة) is compete
وَفِي ذَٰلِكَ فَلْيَتَنَافَسِ الْمُتَنَافِسُونَ
Sabiqoo(سابقو) race! Sarioo(سارعو) - hasten!
So, when it comes to Aakhirah(آخرة), you need to compete and think about it as a race
you're in competition because there's specific places in Jannah(جنة)
and out of every 1000 human beings only one will make it to Jannah(جنة)
Nine hundred ninety nine(999) are going to Hellfire according to the Hadith(حديث) in Sahih Muslim(صحيح مسلم).
Allahعَزّوجَلّ will bring Adam عليه السّلام and tell him,
أخْرِجْ بَعثَ النَّار
Send out the portion of your children that are going to hellfire.
So, Adam عليه السّلام will say,
وَمَا بَعْثَ النَّار
What portion of my children are going to hellfire.?
Allahعَزّوجَلّ will tell Adam(آدم) out of every thousand, 999!
So, Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه was ahead.
And that's something that you noticed throughout his life, he would always come out the first.
And the amazing thing is that it didn't seem as if Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه was doing it to compete with anyone.
It came natural, see with others they were trying to compete with him.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab رضي الله عنه is trying to compete with Abu Bakr(ابوبكر),
Ali Bin Abi Talib(علي بن ابي طالب) is trying to compete with Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
But Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) is doing it as if, even if he's living alone, he's still going to do the same thing
That was his natural way, Poet says;
مَنْ لِي بِمِثْلِ مَشِّكَل الْمُدَلَّلِ تَمْشِي رُوَيْدًا وَتَجِي الْأَوَّلِ
How can I compete with you, when you're walking calmly
and with confidence and you still come the first.
I mean, It doesn't appear that you're trying to rush it, or hasten, but you still come out the first.
So I think that the best way to start this whole series is a statement of Ali Bin Abi Talib(علي بن ابي طالب)
هُوَّ السَّباقْ
he was the first.
And I asked myself the question, how did, he do it.?
How did he pull off such a feel.?
How did he make it.?
You know, because as a human being, you have something against you,
your age, your mental abilities, body strength
but somehow it seems that Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه was able to defy all the odds.
Because in terms of body strength Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه was described as being
you know it might be a good time to give you a physical description of Abu Bakr (ابوبكر), so you could imagine him.
See in this series,
we want to try to not only talk about the events and affairs that happened with Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابو بكرالصديق)
but we want to dig deep into the personality of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
We want to try to live with him.
Try to see how Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) was, from the inside.
So try to imagine, and ponder upon it, because with these people, with the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم
the more you learn about them, the more you would love them.
See it's not like some personalities, in history they have a bright side and a dark side.
With the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم no matter how deep you dig,
All what you would find is good, like Ibn Abbas رضي الله عنه says About Abu Bakr(ابوبكر)
كَانَ خَيْرًا كُلَّه
all of him was good, everything about him was good.
So, we want to try to live with the person of Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابو بكرالصديق)
and learn about him and see the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم, every one of them was different.
Abu Bakr (ابوبكر) was soft and compassionate, very social
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) was stern and firm.
Now, Subhaan Allah(سبحان الله) you will find this during our series of talks on As-Siddique(الصديق),
whenever you talk about Abu Bakr(ابوبكر), you end up talking about Umar(عمر).
And whenever you talk about Umar(عمر), you end up talking about Abu Bakr(ابوبكر)
one of them brings the other, as if they were the two wings of Islam.
And whenever Rasool Allah ﷺ would be seen
people would see with him Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) on one side and Umar(عمر) on the other.
Ali Bin Abi Talib(علي بن ابي طالب) says,
دَخَل رسول الله وَ ابو بكر وعمر
خَرَجَ رسول الله وَ ابو بكر وعمر
Rasool Allah ﷺ would go out with Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) and Umar(عمر).
And he would come back with Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) and Umar(عمر).
So, Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه represents the soft and compassionate and merciful side.
While Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) represents the punishment of Allah on evil.
I mean, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) was the worst thing that happened to Shaytaan(شيطان).
Whenever Shaytaan(شيطان) would see Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) he would have a bad day.
Therefore, whenever Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) would be following the path, Rasool Allah ﷺ would say
Shaytaan(شيطان) would take another path, he would try to avoid you.
because whenever he sees Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب), he brings bad memories to him.
So, they represent two different sides.
Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) represents Shyness.
Ali Bin Abi Talib(علي بن ابي طالب) represents the warrior.
With the wives of Rasool Allah ﷺ, Ayesha رضي الله عنها represents the inquisitive person, who's always asking
eager to learn knowledge, you find that a lot with, young people.
While Khadijah رضي الله عنها, she has more of an attitude of a mature woman.
So she was more of a psychological support of Rasool Allah ﷺ
and whenever Rasool Allah ﷺ would need someone to lean on.
He would find his wife Khadijah رضي الله عنها.
So every Sahabi(صحابي), has a personality.
And you want to learn about the personality of a Sahabi(صحابي),
Abu Dhar(ابو زر) Al-Ghaffari رضي الله عنه, is alone.
In fact, there's a narration
that he became Muslim alone,
he dies alone, and he will be resurrected on the Day of Judgment alone.
Because Abu Dhar Al-Ghaffari رضي الله عنه, was brought up in Ghaffar(غفار).
Now, Ghaffar(غفار) were not businessmen like the people of Makkah
nor were they in agriculture and farming like the people of Madina.
The people Ghaffar(غفار), how did they make a living? By raiding caravans!
That was their business
raiding the caravans, of others.
So, Abu Dhar Al-Ghaffari(ابوزرالغفاري), had to leave his people, because of their evil, he left them.
And he lived alone in the desert, and he became Muslim alone.
And then Rasool Allah ﷺ send him back to make Da'wah(دعوة) to his people.
And he came back and he was successful, he brought in all of his people as Muslim.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ knew that ability with Abu Dhar Al-Ghaffari رضي الله عنه,
but Rasool Allah ﷺ also knew other parts of his personality, so he told him, explicitly.
لاَ تَأَمَّرَنَّ عَلَى اثْنَينِ، وَلاَ تَوَلَّيَنَّ مَالَ يَتِيمٍ
Never assume responsibility even over two people,
and never take care of the financial affairs of an orphan.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ knew the limitations of his personality.
He was good on one thing but some things, Rasool Allah ﷺ told him to avoid.
Abu Darda(ابودردا), he was a Aabid(عابد), a Zahid(زاهد)
He lives a very austere life.
Abdur Rahman Ibn Auf(عبدالرحمن ابن عوف) on the other hand was a millionaire.
In fact, they say that Abdur Rahman Ibn Auf(عبدالرحمن ابن عوف), when he passed away.
Subhan Allah(سبحان الله), you know some people
Wealth just flocks towards them.
Abdur Rahman Ibn Auf رضي الله عنه, when he made Hijrah(هجرة) from Makkah to Madina
he came broke, he had nothing, whatsoever.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ puts him in Akhhua(اخوة) - brotherhood with Saad Ibn Ubadah(سعد ابن عبادة),
one of the wealthy leaders of Al-Ansaar(الانصار).
Saad Ibn Ubadah(سعد ابن عبادة) told Abdur Rahman Ibn Auf(عبدالرحمن ابن عوف);
If you want I will split my wealth in two
and I have two wives, I will divorce one of them, and marry her to you, and you choose which one you want.
Look at the level of brotherhood, and sacrifice that Al-Ansaar(الانصار) had.
Keep in mind that they were new Muslim, I mean it's not that they went through Tarbiah(تربيعة) for a very long time.
They just became Muslim but they had the spirit.
Abdur Rahman Ibn Auf(عبدالرحمن ابن عوف) could have picked up this opportunity,
half of the wealth of Saad Ibn Ubadah(سعد ابن عبادة), offered voluntarily.
But he said: No, may Allah give you blessing in your family and your wealth.
And then, what did he say.?
I just want you to point out to me, where the market of Madina is.?
دُلَّنِيْ عَلى سٌوق الْمَدينَه
Show me where the market is.?
That's all what I need.
He showed him, the market of Madina
a very short while later,
Rasool Allah ﷺ saw Abdur Rahman Ibn Auf(عبدالرحمن ابن عوف) with some yellow powder on his face
that yellow powder, was the makeup that they used to use, in Jahiliyyah(جَاهلِيَّة) for women.
It was makeup for women, it's a yellow powder.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ asked him where is that powder from.? He said: I got married.
So, that powder was on his face.
He said: I got married.
Rasool Allah ﷺ asked him and what did you pay her in Mahar(مهر), you just came from Makkah and you are broke.
He said: I gave her gold.
He has already made enough wealth to buy gold and give it as a Mahar(مهر) to his wife.
When Abdur Rahman Ibn Auf(عبدالرحمن ابن عوف) passed away, or before I talked about when he passed away.
One day, people are feeling some tremble and shaking in Madina.
So, they asked what it was.?
They said: The caravan of Abdur Rahman Ibn Auf(عبدالرحمن ابن عوف) has arrived from Syria.
There are so many camels in it, you could feel the earth, shaking.
That is how wealthy, he became.
Allah سبحانه تعالى has blessed, his wealth.
Anyway, when he passed away he split up his wealth and gave it to his family members.
But there was so much of it that he ended up separating part of his wealth and writing in his will
that I want you to split it among all of the Muslims, who fought in the Battle of Badr(بدر)
every one of the Muslims who fought in the battle of Badr(بدر), who were still alive
Give him part of my inheritance.
Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) was one of the ones who fought in the Battle of Badr(بدر)
and he was at the time a Khalifah(خليفه)
but he still accepted his portion from the inheritance of Abdur Rahman Ibn Auf(عبدالرحمن ابن عوف).
Because Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) said:
The wealth of Abdur Rahman Ibn Auf(عبدالرحمن ابن عوف) is pure Halal - 100%.
So how can I turn down, such a gift from Allah.
This is a wealth that has Barakah(بركة) in it, it's all Halal(حلال).
So, how can I turn it down.
Even though Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) himself, was he was a wealthy man
and he was the Khalifah(خليفه).
So, the Sahabah(صحابه) were different but it's important to learn about them.
Why because we cannot be the same
we have different abilities, we have different skills.
Not everyone will be like Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب),
nor will everyone be like the personality of Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابو بكر الصديق),
but you could be like Muadh Ibn Jabal(معاز ابن جبل),
a scholar, or you could be a Mujahid(مجاهد) like Khalid Ibn Waleed(خالد ابن وليد).
There are different roles.
So, it's important to study about the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم so that you could look up to one of them
and try to be like them.
The one that your personality, most closely resembles
you can take such a Sahabi(صحابي), as a role model and the same has to be said about the sisters.
By looking at Umma Ha Tul-Moemineen(اُمَّهات المؤمنين) and looking at the Sahabiaat(صحابيات).
Try to find for yourself a role model to follow.
Now, our lives could be mediocre and normal - I mean, usually on a daily basis, there's not a lot happening
not many events going on,
but there would be a day in your life, where you where you are faced with a situation
that would change the course of your future.
These are called Muaqiff(مواقف) in Arabic, it's called Muaqiff(مواقف),
Muaqiff(مواقف) one could translate it literally, it means a standing point - It's a moment!
It's one moment in your life, but it will change the course of your life.
And these Muaqiff(مواقف) are the critical moments in your life that reveal, who you really are.?
These are the tests that you will be faced with
maybe on a daily basis, things are going normal and regular there's nothing really different.
But there will be one day in a year or one day in a month,
when something important will happen, and Allah is testing you through that stand.
Where would you stand, which position will you take.?
If we look at the life of Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه, we don't have his entire life record with us.
We don't have the 365 days of every year of his life in front of us,
but we do have a few stations in his life that tell us who Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) was.
And some of these stations were a matter of seconds.
Some of them were longer.
So sometimes hours or days or months could pass in your life insignificantly.
But then one second, would make a difference.
And that's Rasool Allah ﷺ says:
One of you could speak one word, because of that word that would be raised up Jannah(جنة).
And they could speak one word that would anger Allah.
That would cause them to throw in hellfire for 70 years.
Just one word, but that's a Muaqiff(مؤقف), that's a standing point,
a pivotal point in your life.
If we look at the life of Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) there are many of these Muaqiff(مواقف).
Many of these standing points, but five of them are especially unique,
Number one, His Islam.
With everyone else, there was a Qubwah(قبوة), you know, there's a saying in Arabic
لِكُل حسانٍ قَبْوَةْ
For every horse, there is a stumble
every horse, at one moment of time, it will make a slip, it will trip and fall down.
No matter how perfect, the horse is, that will one day happen.
Now, with every person who became Muslim, there was such a moment of hesitation
giving it a second thought, sitting over it for a day thinking about it, with the exception of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
As soon as the message was presented to him, he said:
أَشْهَدُ أَنْ لَا إِلَهَ إِلَّا اللَّهُ وَأَشْهَدُ أَنَّ مُحَمَّدًاَرَسُولَ الله
He did not give it a second thought.
Not because Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) was an easy person to convince,
not because Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) change his mind easily.
In fact, Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) was very decisive in his decisions.
And that is very apparent when he became a Khalifah(خليفه).
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه has the ability to stand up firmly,
against all of the Sahabah(صحابه) on a few issues and in the end it turns out that he was right.
So, it's not like a person that is, he could be easily convinced one way or another.
- No, that wasn't the personality of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) when he became Muslim, he knew exactly what he was getting his feet into.
But we'll talk about that in his Islam.
Why?
why did Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) immediately accept Islam.?
Why didn't he give it a second thought - How come it was immediate? We'll get to that!
So, this is the first Muaqiff(مؤقف) in the life of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
The second standing point, unique point in the life of a Siddique رضي الله عنه, is Al-Israa Wal-Meraaj(الاسرآء ولمعراج)
and I'm going through these briefly because I'll talk about them later in more detail.
When this amazing journey happened with Rasool Allah ﷺ,
the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) being secular people materialistic people,
who only believe in what their eyes can see and what their ears can hear, and what their hands can touch.
They made a joke out of Al-Israa Wal-Meraaj(الاسرآء ولمعراج), they made fun of it.
And they thought that this is their chance to bring an end to Islam,
all of the Muslims will give up their religion they will think that their prophet is insane.
So, Abu Jahal(ابوجهل) was very happy.
So they went to Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق), who wasn't there, he hasn't met with Rasool Allah ﷺ yet.
So one of the Kuffar(كفار) went to him and said: Do you know what your friend is claiming.?
Do you know what, he said?
He's claiming that he has visited Jerusalem and came back in the same night.
What was a response of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).?
Now, if Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه had weak Eeman(ايمان).
He would say that's not true,
and if Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه was a type of person, who could be easily deceived.
He would say: Yes that happened.
But Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق), since the source that is speaking to him, is one of Al-Kuffar(الكفار).
So, can't take them at face value.
And at the same time, Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) does not want to reject
something that Rasool Allah ﷺ could have said.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) said in a brief statement.
اِنْ كَانَ قَالَهَا فَقَد صَدَقْ
If Rasool Allah ﷺ said so, then it's the truth.
So, there's two parts of the statement, number one, if Rasool Allah ﷺ said so.
First of all I have to verify it.
If he did say it, then it's the truth.
And this is the Manhaj(منهج) of Hadith(حديث).
That is the Manhaj(منهج) of Ulema(علماء) Al-Hadith(الحديث).
If Rasool Allah ﷺ said it, then it's the truth.
So, we have to verify it first.
We don't just accept it, at face value, when the narration could be weak
we have to study the narration.
If it's established, that it's Sahih(صحيح), we won't reject it.
We won't turn it down, we won't say it is illogical, this goes against the civilized, 21st century, No!.
We would accept it.
As long as Rasool Allah ﷺ said it, then it's right, it's true, it's Wahii(وحي) from Allah.
The third standing point is during the death of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
The historians, describe that moment, by saying:
when Rasool Allah ﷺ died, Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) was hiding in his house.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) was carrying his sword and claiming that Muhammadﷺ did not die,
but he went to meet Allah for 40 days, like Musa(موسى) went to meet Allah and he will be back.
And whoever claims that Muhammad(محمد) has died, I will cut off his head.
And some of the Sahabah(صحابه) were in the Masjid(مسجد), crying.
That's how they give a description of the situation in Madina after Rasool Allah ﷺ passed away.
It was such a catastrophe that they weren't able to handle it.
Now even though Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه has the closest relationship with Rasool Allah ﷺ, of all of the Sahabah(صحابه).
He was the one, who brought them back.
It was Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه who brought them back.
So, it shows you the steadfastness, the Thabaat(ثبات),
and the Eeman(ايمان) and the Yaqeen(يقين) that Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه had, that's the third.
The fourth pivotal point, in his life before Rasool Allah ﷺ passed away.
He appointed Osama Bin Zaid(اسامه.بن زيد) to lead an army.
And he gave them the following instructions.
But before I give his instructions, just a little bit background information.
Rasool Allah ﷺ appointed Zaid Bin Harissa(زيد بن حارثه) his former adopted son, a former slave
to lead an army that had a nobility of the Sahabah(صحابه) in it.
And he ordered this army to go and fight with the Romans.
The first confrontation with the Roman Empire.
Rasool Allah ﷺ appointed Zaid Bin Harissa(زيد بن حارثه) to be the Ameer(امير) of the army.
Subhaan Allah(سبحان الله) Rasool Allah ﷺ has given instructions on what to do.
If the Ameer(امير) dies.
So he said: If Zaid Bin Harissa(زيد بن حارثه) dies,
then Jafar Ibn Abi Talib(جعفر ابن ابي طالب) is the Ameer(امير)
If he dies then Abdullah Bin Rawaha(عبدالله بن رواحة) is the Ameer(امير).
Because this was such a risky operation, Rasool Allah ﷺ gave these three names
because now the Muslims are going to be facing the Roman Empire.
And he gave his orders to them and they went up north to face with the Roman Empire.
The first battle ever between Islam and the Romans.
The army was 2000 soldiers and they were facing an army of 200,000.
In one narration it says that it was 400,000.
Anyway, so the three Umaraa(امرآء) were killed.
And then the Muslims agreed to appoint Khalid Ibn Walid(خالد ابن وليد) as the Ameer(امير) of the army
and he made a successful retreat back to Al-Madina.
Now Usama Bin Zaid(أسامه بن زيد) is the son of Zaid Bin Haritha(زيد بن حارثه).
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ a few days before he passes away,
he appoints Osama Bin Zaid(اسامه بن زيد) to lead an army and he gives him the following instructions, he says:
I want you to lead this army, and to step with your horses over the land, where your father was killed.
So, take this army to the same place, where your father was killed, and I wanted to step with your horses over it.
- But Rasool Allah ﷺ passed away before the army left.
Now, Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه became Khalifah(خليفه)
and the tribes surrounding Madina, apostated.
So, the Sahabah(صحابه) were coming to Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه, and telling him.
This army of Osama(اسامه) that's supposed to go and fight the Romans, keep it in Madina, to protect Madina
because this is our priority.
This is where the Sahabah(صحابه) are,
and this is where the family of Rasool Allah ﷺ is, and it's our responsibility to protect them.
This is where the army should stay. Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه said:
Do you want me to reverse an order that was given by Rasool Allah ﷺ?
It was Rasool Allah ﷺ who send this army out and it will go out.
And even if everyone in Madina is killed, and I'm the only one alive.
I'm still going to send this army out.
And we'll talk about the implications of this order later on.
And the final stand was the position of Al-Siddique(الصديق) regarding Al-Murtaddeen(المرتدين).
Now, why history?
Why talk about history, why is it important?
Muslim youth today, especially in the West, are lacking an identity.
We have an identity crisis.
Ask our young brothers and sisters who are brought up in the West, about the Anbiyaa(انبياء) of Allah,
ask them about Sahabah(صحابه), and then ask them about superstars.
Ask them about celebrities, just to give you an example
I was once talking about Al-Hajjaj Bin Yousuf As-Saqqafi(الحجاج بن يوسف الثقفي).
I was speaking to a group of young brothers and sisters in the West.
Al-Hajjaj Bin Yousuf As-Saqqafi(الحجاج بن يوسف الثقفي) was the leader of Iraq in the time of Umviyeen(امويين),
decades, decades after Rasool Allah ﷺ passed away.
His name is Al-Hajjaj Bin Yousuf(الحجاج بن يوسف) and he was a very brutal dictator, tyannical ruler.
He killed many of the Taba'een(تابعين).
After I finish the talk, one brother, teenager walking up to me and said: I have a question!
How can Al-Hajjaj Bin Yousuf(الحجاج بن يوسف) be so bad and horrible.
If he's the son of Yousaf عليه السّلام.?
Difference of thousands of years, I mean,
but I might ask the same person about a singer, an actor or a football player
and they would know the ins and out of that personality.
So, there is an identity crisis and when I'm saying this, the blame is not on the youth.
The youth cannot be blamed for this.
Families, who are raising up their children in such an environment, need to take up their responsibility
because the school is not gonna teach this, nor with the media teach it.
The media is not going to talk about the Anbiya(انبياء) and the Sahabah(صحابه)
- nor will the public school system talk about them.
The public school system will tell you about the heroes of the American Civil War and the heroes of Imperial Britain.
- And the colonial era and the kings and queens of the respective countries.
But they're not going to talk about Khalid Ibn Waleed(خالد ابن وليد).
They're not going to talk about Musa عليه السّلام or Eesa عليه السّلام or Ibrahim عليه السّلام.
They're not going to talk about Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) and Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنهم.
They're not going to talk about Ayesha رضي الله عنها or Khadijah(خديجه).
So, our youth are deprived of this information.
Now, as one famous writer says: If you want to destroy a society sever their roots,
cut off the roots, and the tree will dry out and die.
If you don't have an attachment to your heritage,
if you do not have an attachment to your history, you're nobody.
Therefore it's extremely important for every one of us, to learn the details of the lives of our heroes.
These are our celebrities, these are our role models, these are the ones we want to follow.
It's not enough just to know the name because you can't love a person, if you just know them by name.
You have to know more about them.
And Subhan Allah(سبحان الله) with these people, the more you know about them, the more you love them.
And with the celebrities of the kuffar(كفار), the more you know about them, the more you hate them.
If you have the correct Fitrah(فطرة) natural disposition, because Rasool Allah ﷺ says, that the time will come.
ياتي على الناس زمان  يقالو فيه الرجل مَا أَجْلَدَهُ! مَا أَظْرَفَهُ! مَا أَعْقَلَهُ! وَمَا فِي قَلْبِهِ مِثْقَالُ حَبَّةٍ مِنْ خَرْدَلٍ مِنْ إِيمَانٍ
Rasool Allah ﷺ says the time will come when people will say about a man.
مَا أَظْرَفَهُ
Now if I want to translate the word - مَا أَظْرَفَهُ - Literally
that person is cool!
- Look at how cool that person is. Now who are the people, whom are called Cool today.
Who are they - Who are the ones, who are called cool? This person is cool!
Rasool Allah ﷺ says, the time will come, when they will say about the person he is
مَا أَظْرَفَهُ
He is cool - When there's not a single grain of Eeman(إيمان) in his heart, we're living in those times.
So we need to learn about the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم, now the important part of our history is - the Ambiya(انبياء) of Allah
Muhammadﷺ, and the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم, because Ambiya(انبياء) of Allah, are the greatest of humanity
and the second best are Sahabah رضي الله عنهم.
So these are the two groups that we should focus on.
Now when we're talking about Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه,
we're not only talking about the person of Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق)
but we're also talking about the time of Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق).
So we're going to be talking about his Khilafah(خلافه) and what happened in his Khilafah(خلافه).
So that will be a way for us to know, about Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) and the times of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
What are the sources that I've referred to?
In terms of the classical source that I've used it's a Tabari(الطبري), Tareekh At-Tabari(التاريخ الطبري),
there are many different historical writers by our classical scholars the earliest one of them is At-Tabari(الطبري)
and then you have Ibn Kathir(ابن كثير) also, Al-Bidayah Wan Nihayah(البدايه والنهايه),
Tareekh-Ul-Khulafah(تاريخ الخلفاء) by As-Suyuti(السيوطي).
So there are many sources, the one that I am using for this particular series is Tareekh At-Tabari(التاريخ الطبري),
the history of At-Tabari(الطبري).
Contemporary sources, an excellent book written by Shaikh Ali Assallabi(شيخ علي الصلابي).
who has done excellent research in visiting all of the classical books and drawing from each one of them.
The most important and valid pieces of information
and he wrote an excellent book about Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه.
And then in terms of audio tapes, the tapes of Amr Khalid(عمرو خالد) and Tariq Suwedaan(طارق سويدان) are also beneficial.
Basically everyone is going back to the same sources, same classical sources.
That's the fountain of knowledge.
So, whether it is audio tapes or contemporary books, it is all going back to the original sources.
It's just a matter of how much research you did and what particular information you chose.
And it depends on how strict the person is, in terms of the authenticity
of the narrations because in the classical sources you'll find both weak and strong.
So everyone now, is pretty much going back to At-Tabari(الطبري) and Ibn Kathir(ابن كثير)
and As-Suyuti(السيوطي) and others.
The name Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه, his real name is not Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
That was the name given to him by the people - it's a nickname.
But his original name according to the majority of the scholars is Abdullah(عبدالله)
some say that his name is Ateeq(عتيق)
but most likely Ateeq(عتيق) is a description of Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق)
or a name that was given to him by Rasool Allah ﷺ.
But his original name, the name that was given to him by his parents is Abdullah(عبدالله),
his father, is nicknamed Abu Quhafah(ابوقحافه) and you see, you find that the names that we know
them with are usually not the original names.
For example, with Rasool Allah ﷺ,
the name of his grandfather is Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) and that's not his original name
his original name is Shaibah(شيبه).
And he was named Shaibah(شيبه), which means old man.
Because when he was born, it says that he has some gray hair.
So they call him Shaibah(شيبه).
But he was called Abdul Muttalib(عبدالمطلب) because one day his uncle was bringing him into Makkah.
So people thought that he's a slave boy.
They thought that his uncle went out to the market and bought the slaves.
So they called him Abdul Muttalib(عبدالمطلب), the slave of Al-Muttalib(المطلب).
The name of the uncle was Al-Muttalib(المطلب).
So they called him the slave of Al-Muttalib(المطلب).
So that name was the name that he later became famous with.
And then Abdul Muttalib Bin Hashim(عبدالمطلب بن هاشم).
Now Hashim(هاشم) is also not his original name, his name is Amr(عمرو).
But Hashim(هاشم) means crushing, something that is crushed.
And Hashim(هاشم) was given that name because he was the first one to crush bread in soup,
and give it to the pilgrims before they would only give them soup.
But out of his added generosity, he put in the soup bread and he crushed it.
So, he is called Hashim(هاشم).
So, that was a habit in Arabia that you will be given a name but later on - you will pick up a new name.
So, the father of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) was called Abu Quhafah(ابوقحافه) but his real name was Uthman(عثمان).
So Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق), his name is Abdullah Bin Uthman(عبدالله بن عثمان).
He was named Abu Bakr(ابوبكر), the father of Bakr(بكر) or the one of Bakr(بكر),
Abu(ابو) could mean either father or the one of.
Bakr(بكر) means a young lively camel.
A young lively camel, so it's not an old camel.
And it's not middle aged, it's young, but it's very lively and full of vigor, strong.
By the way, during the wars with Al-Murtaddeen(المرتدين), these Arab tribes who apostated
they said: We're not going to pay our money to Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق), who is he.?
We used to pay our money to the Messenger of Allah, Muhammadﷺ,
so that it would purify us from our sins but we're not going to pay it to Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
And they started calling him, Abul Faseel(ابوالفصيل)
Al-Faseel(الفصيل) means the infant camel,
so they want to indicate that Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق), was a weak man, we're not gonna pay our money, to him.
Abul Faseel(ابوالفصيل), who's Abul Faseel(ابولفصيل).?
So Udae Ibn Hatim(عدي ابن هاتم) was telling them, that you will come to realize that he is Abul Fahal(ابو الفهل)
you will come to realize that he is the one of the stallion, not only Bakr(بكر) but he is the stallion, Abul Fahal(ابوالفهل)
and Udae Ibn Hatim(عدي ابن هاتم) his words turned out to be true.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) subdue them in the end
and they came to realize, who Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) really was!
Anyway, so that was name Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
The titles that were given to him, the most famous one is As-Siddique(الصديق),
which is derived from As-Siddq(الصدق) truth.
Why was he given that name?
Well, there are a few instances that happened in his life.
The one that Ayesha(عائشه) mentions, she says, she mentions the story of Al-Israa(الاسرآء).
If he said it, then is the truth.
So Ayesha(عائشه) say, he was called As-Siddique(الصديق), the believing
- and this is narrated in Al-Hakim(الحاكم).
Rasool Allah ﷺ has also called him As-Siddique(الصديق).
Rasool Allah ﷺ one day was standing on Uhud(أحَد) along with Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) and Umar(عمر) and Uthman(عثمان).
So there was a slight earthquake. So, Rasool Allah ﷺ put his hand on the mountain and said,
أثْبُتْ أحُدْ
Uhud(أحَد) stay firm. Because on top of you, is a prophet, a Siddique(الصديق) and two martyrs
- and the mountain stopped moving.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ called Abu Bakr - As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق), and he called Umar(عمر) and Uthman(عثمان) - Shuhadah(شهداء).
اِنَّما عَلَيك نَبِيٌ وَصديق وَشَهِيْدَيْنْ
He was also called As-Siddique(الصديق) because he was very fast in accepting Islam.
And this is the most famous name, another name given to Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه is As-Sahibb(الصاحب)
- The companion.
All of the Sahabah(صحابه) were companions, but the companionship of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) was unique
Rasool Allah ﷺ and Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) had special relationship.
They were very close together, even before Islam. And they were close in age.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) was only two years younger than Rasool Allah ﷺ.
- While the other Sahabah(صحابه) were very young. And Ali Bin Abi Talib(علي بن ابي طالب) was a child.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) was considered to be among the seniors of As-Sahabah(الصحابه),
he was only 28 years old when he became Muslim.
However, Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) was 38, when he became Muslim, so he was among the closest of the Sahabah(صحابه)
- to the age of Muhammadﷺ.
Rasool Allah ﷺ, Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) had a very close relationship before Islam
- very close friendship and Islam only strengthen it further.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه was so close to Muhammadﷺ as if he was created for him
- I mean Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه was not only a friend, he was a companion
an advisor
a financial supporter
a bodyguard
a confident
he was everything for Muhammad صلوات الله وسلام عليه.
And this name was given to Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) in Qur'an.
Allahعَزّوجَلّ says about the journey of Al-Hijrah(الحجرة).
إِلَّا تَنْصُرُوهُ فَقَدْ نَصَرَهُ اللَّهُ
إِذْ أَخْرَجَهُ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا ثَانِيَ اثْنَيْنِ إِذْ هُمَا فِي الْغَارِ إِذْ يَقُولُ لِصَاحِبِهِ
لَا تَحْزَنْ إِنَّ اللَّهَ مَعَنَا
فَأَنْزَلَ اللَّهُ سَكِينَتَهُ عَلَيْهِ وَأَيَّدَهُ بِجُنُودٍ لَمْ تَرَوْهَا
Allahعَزّوجَلّ says, If you do not aid him, Allah has already aided him.
When those, who disbelieved had driven him out, as one of two, when they were in the cave and he said to his companion.
So, he is called in Qur'an, the companion of Muhammadﷺ, do not grieve, Indeed Allah is with us.
And Allah sent down his tranquility upon him, and supported him with soldiers, you did not see
- and made the word of those who disbelieved, the lowest, while the word of Allah that is the highest
- and Allah is Exalted in Might and Wise.
Ibn Hajar Al-Asqalani(ابن حجر العسقلاني) comments on this Ayah(آية), and says,
فإن المراد بصاحبه هنا أبو بكر بلا منازع،
والأحاديث في كونه كان معه في الغار كثيرة مشهورة، ولم يشركه في المنقبة غيره
Ibn Hajar(ابن حجر) says, the companion in this Ayah(آية) is Abu Bakr(ابوبكر)
according to the consensus of the scholars and there are many ahadith(احاديث) to state that.
And there is no one, who shared this unique quality with Rasool Allah ﷺ except Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
Another name is Al-Ateeq(العتيق), Al-Ateeq(العتيق) means the emancipated.
- The one who's freed from slavery, the one who is liberated.
Now Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) is never really a slave in the worldly sense
- so what is meant by Al-Ateeq(العتيق)?
Because when the slave is freed, Al-Atq(العتق), freeing slaves is Al-Atq(العتق),
so Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) was called Al-Ateeq(العتيق), the one who's freed, emancipated.
What is meant by this Ayesha رضي الله عنها says, That Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه came to Rasool Allah ﷺ.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ looked at him and said:
أبشر يا ابا بكر فأنت عتيق اللـه من النار
O Abu Bakr(ابوبكر), receive the glad tidings and rejoice. You are the freed slave of Allah, from hellfire.
He's also called Al-Atqaa(العتقه). Al-Atqaa(العتقه) means the most pious.
And he was given that title in Qur'an In Surat Al-Lail(سورة اليل),
وَسَيُجَنَّبُهَا الْأَتْقَى ۝ الَّذِي يُؤْتِي مَالَهُ يَتَزَكَّىٰ۝
The reasoning behind this, is that Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) and we'll talk about the details of this.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) used to free slaves, the Muslim slaves,
who were under persecution he would buy them and free them.
But the slaves he would free, were weak, women.
Now, the tradition was in Arabia that when you free a slave,
that slave retains a relationship of loyalty with you because you are the one who freed the slave.
So, slave has special loyalty with you when they're freed.
It's not a relationship of slavery anymore but it's a relationship of strong loyalty.
The father of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر), went to Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) and told him my son,
how come you are freeing these weak slaves, women and children?
Why don't you free, if you're going to free slaves, why don't you free some strong men?
- so that one day they will support you.?
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه said:
The reason I'm doing this is to please Allah
I'm not looking for any worldly benefit. So, Allahعَزّوجَلّ revealed the last Ayaat(آيات) in Surat Ul Lail(سورة اليل),
وَسَيُجَنَّبُهَا الْأَتْقَى ۝
الَّذِي يُؤْتِي مَالَهُ يَتَزَكَّىٰ ۝
وَمَا لِأَحَدٍ عِنْدَهُ مِنْ نِعْمَةٍ تُجْزَىٰ ۝ إ
ِلَّا ابْتِغَاءَ وَجْهِ رَبِّهِ الْأَعْلَىٰ ۝ وَلَسَوْفَ يَرْضَىٰ۝
Allahعَزّوجَلّ says But the righteous one, will avoid it.
He, who gives from his wealth to purify himself and not giving for anyone who has done him a favor to be rewarded.
He's not paying back anyone he is not doing it for a reward himself,
but only seeking the countenance of his Lord most high and he is going to be satisfied.
Allahعَزّوجَلّ says, he is going to be satisfied.
Allahعَزّوجَلّ will make Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) happy.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه was born two years after the year of the elephant,
because the Arabs did not have a calendar system.
So, whenever an important event would happen, they would call that year after this event.
So when Allah destroyed the army of Abraha(ابراهة) that year was called Aam El- Feel(عام الفيل), the year of the elephant.
Later on, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) developed the calendar
- because Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) when he became Khalifah(خليفه), there were a few cases that were taken to court.
For example, you would say I gave that person a loan. And here's the contract, you pay me back in Shaban(شعبان).
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) said: The problem is, it doesn't say Shaban(شعبان) which year
they didn't have a calendar.
So, it just say, Shaban(شعبان), Shaban(شعبان) this year, last year, 10 years from now.
So Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) said: We have to sort that thing out
- we have to have our calendar.
Now, Islam is a Khilafah(خلافه).
It's not within a small group where everybody knows each other, we have to establish a system.
And that's when they adopted Al-Hijrah(الهجره) but before that it was the year of the elephant.
So, Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) was born two years after the year of the elephant
- and Rasool Allah ﷺ was born a few weeks after the event of the elephant.
So, there was a two year difference between them.
I want to give you a physical description of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر)
- it's not much that exists, but at least you can develop a mental picture of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر),
because you imagine a certain image of a person and that image could be wrong.
Now the image helps you understand about the person when you look at the person.
Especially if you have Farasah(فراسه),
Farasah(فراسه) is the art of reading the face, you could tell a lot about that person
- and the Arabs used to study this science and it says that Ash-Shafie(الشافعي) went to study Farasah(فراسه) in Yemen.
So it was a science that was taught or an art actually, it is reading the face.
It says that Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) was one of the people, who were good at it.
He saw someone and he asked him, what's your name? He said: My name is flame.
He said, What's your family name?
He said: My family name is Spark.
What's his tribe name? He said: My tribe name is fire.
He said: Well go back home because your house is on fire and it turned out to be true.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) saw another man.
He just looked at his face and said: This man is a magician, or he was a magician,
So, they call the man and he said: Yes, I used to be a sorcerer in Jahiliyyah(جَاهلِيَّة).
He saw it, in his face.
So then Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) asked him, What is the strangest thing that you heard from Al-Jinn(الجن)?
So, he mentioned some poetry that was talking about the coming of Muhammadﷺ, that he heard from Al-Jinn(الجن)
so you want to develop a mental picture and again, you'll find the contrasting,
mental picture between Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) and Umar(عمر).
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه was medium to short in height and he was very slim, slender.
In fact extremely slim.
When Rasool Allah ﷺ said that you have should have your Izaar(إزار) above the ankle.
Al-Izaar(الإزار) is like a towel or a Longi(لونكي), but a Longi(لونكى) is a the tide is circular
the Izaar(ازار) is open, they would wrap one towel on the bottom half.
And if they have enough money, then they would buy a second piece to cover their top
- Otherwise they would not cover the shoulders.
That was it, like Al-Ihraam(الاحرام) basically that was their clothes.
Obviously there were different types of clothes that they had, but this was the predominant one.
So, Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) when he heard Rasool Allah ﷺ say
that the Izaar(ازار) should be above the ankle. He went to Rasool Allah ﷺ and said:
يا رسول الله اِنَّ اَزاري لَا يَسْتَمْسِكُو على حقوي
O messenger of Allah, my Izaar(ازار) is not holding on to my waist.
He was so slim that his Izaar(ازار) would not hold to his waist and it would fall down.
So the Izaar(ازار) would go under the ankle. So, is there anything wrong with that?
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: No! not for you.
That is how slim Abu Bakr(ابو بكر) was, the Izaar(ازار) wouldn't even hold on his waist
- and he was described as having very slim legs. In fact, his entire body, didn't have a lot of flesh, even his face
- you could see the bones on his cheek,
وكان غارالعينين
And his eyes were deep in the socket. And he was very fair skin.
He was described as being white, Abyadh(ابيض).
Now, this is obviously relative because the Arabs when they would say white, it meant fair skin.
But what we call white now they would call red, when they would say that a person is red or yellow, it means white.
So, don't take the words literally the colors literally when you're reading old Arabic text,
because they would call for example the Europeans Bannu Ul Asfar(بنو الاصفر) the yellow people and Ahmar(احمر) is
they would also call them sometimes Ahmar(احمر), red. White was fair skin relative to the people in the desert
- because usually the people in desert have dark skin. So, relative to that Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق) was fair skin.
He was very social person. He was very approachable and likeable.
Now with Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب), on the other hand, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) was very tall, well built.
So, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) was anything but slim.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) was tall and muscular
and that was also the description given to Khalid Ibn Waleed(خالد ابن وليد).
So both Khalid Ibn Waleed(خالد ابن وليد) and Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب), were very tall, muscular, well built
- and both of them will jump on the horse.
And Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) actually gave advice to the Sahabah(صحابه),
jump on them while the horses are running. Don't stop the horse and ride it.
And Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) has these amazing words of advice,
one have to think about it to get the point, behind it.
He says walk barefoot - Run between the targets. In archery, they would have two targets
- they would stand next to one target and they would throw their arrows
- and then they would walk from this target to the other pick up the arrows - Off the target
- and then shoot at the first target. And he says:
وَخْشَوشَنُوْ
And lead a rough life and stay away from the habits of Al-Ajam(العجم),
stay away from the habits of the non Muslims.
Now one would think why, I have to walk barefoot, I mean, what's the point in that.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) is not saying that you have to walk barefoot everyday
What Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) is saying, that once in a while you want to get yourself ready
and trained for difficult lifestyle.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه was very likable, approachable, people would love to sit with him
talk with him because of his very compassionate nature, very kind.
While Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب), when a thought just passes through your mind
to visit Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب), your knees started to shake, trembling.
He had that strong presence. One day, when he was Khalifah(خليفه),
he was walking with Sahabah(صحابه) down the street in Madina. He just looked behind
- He turned around, there was a pregnant woman behind him, she had a miscarriage.
Some of the Sahabah(صحابه) said: Umar(عمر) needs to pay blood money, it was because of him.
Some of them said: It's not his problem, he just he just turned around.
Ali Bin Abi Talib(علي بن ابي طالب) he gave the right Hukum(حكم), he said:
Well, blood money has to be paid to that poor woman. But it's not Umar(عمر), who should pay it
- Because it's not his fault, we will pay it from the treasury of the Muslims.
That was the personality of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب).
Once Abu Musa Al-Asha'ari(ابوموسى الأشعري), went and he knocked the door of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) three times.
Umar(عمر) did not respond. So, Abu Musa Al-Asha'ari(ابوموسى الأشعري) left.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) called him back. He said; How come you left.?
Abu Musa Al-Asha'ari(ابوموسى الأشعري) said; I heard Rasool Allah ﷺ say:
If you seek permission three times and you're not given permission, then leave.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) said: You're gonna have to bring me a witness that Rasool Allah ﷺ said that
Abu Musa Al-Asha'ari(ابوموسى الأشعري) went, where there was a gathering of Sahabah(صحابه)
When he came in, they saw his face yellow. And they knew that he was terrified.
So, they asked him what happened.? He said: This is what happened?
After that brief conversation, the color of his face changed.
That was a natural posture of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب)
I mean, he wasn't doing it intentionally - His presence projected that impression among people.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه was a seasoned traveler, he was successful businessman
- he has been around, met a lot of people, knows the leaders of the tribes and he was very famous.
In fact, people were more familiar with the face of Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق)
then they were with the face of Muhammadﷺ.
So, in Hijrah(هجرة), people used to come to Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق)
and give him Salaam(سلام) and then they would ask him, Who's this man with you?
Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق) would say;
هذا هدني يهدين الطريق
This man guiding me through my way, now because that trip was top secret
and he had to conceal the identity of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
He said: This man is guiding me. What the questioner would understand is that he's guiding him through the desert.
But what Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق) meant was that he's guiding me to Jannah(جنة)
this man is guiding me to Jannah(جنة).
Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق) was a specialist in genealogy.
He knew the names of the tribes, their origins, where they're from, where they came from, their ancestry.
He was an expert in that field. Ayesha رضي الله عنها says;
اِنَّ اَبَابَكر اَعْلَمَ قُريش بِاَنسابهَا
And this is in Sahih Muslim(صحيح مسلم), Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق) is the best man among Quraish(قُرَيْشْ)
in knowing the origins and the genealogy of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
And this wasn't just historical study.
This was a very important asset for Rasool Allah ﷺ. Therefore whenever Rasool Allah ﷺ
was meeting with the tribes in the season of Hajj(حج), who would he always take along with him?
Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق), because Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق) before Rasool Allah ﷺ meets with any tribe
Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق) would tell him, who they are.? What are they? What are their qualities?
What are the pros and cons of these people? Where they come from.? The location, the topography of the area,
all of that information was in his mind, to the extent that Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق) would even do most of the talking
- and most of the conversation with these people would be done by Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه.
So this was a very important asset for Rasool Allah ﷺ.
There was one thing about the personality of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) and it's seems that this is sometimes a characteristic of aspiring people
and Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق) was a man with great aspirations.
I mean, it's very clear in his life, as we said - هو السباق - he was always the first.
His aspirations were to please Allahعَزّوجَلّ, it wasn't for Duniyah(دُنِيَّا),
his aspirations were for Aakhirah(آخرة), to please Allahعَزّوجَلّ.
وَسَيُجَنَّبُهَا الْأَتْقَى ۝
الَّذِي يُؤْتِي مَالَهُ يَتَزَكَّىٰ ۝ وَمَا لِأَحَدٍ عِنْدَهُ مِنْ نِعْمَةٍ تُجْزَىٰ ۝ إِلَّا ابْتِغَاءَ وَجْهِ رَبِّهِ الْأَعْلَىٰ۝
He's doing it for the sake of Allah.
So he was a very inspiring person.
However, Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه had a slight hot temper and Umar Ibn Al-Khattab رضي الله عنه says;
وَكُنْتُ أدَارِي مِنْه’ بَعْضَ الحَدّ
I used to try to avoid the temper of Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه. And Ibn Abbas رضي الله عنه says:
كان خيرًا كله على حدةٍ كانت فيه
He was all good - Everything about him was good, but he had a hot temper
but he would come back very fast and seek forgiveness and apologize
and his compassionate and kind Nature made it, acceptable to people.
And they appreciate that from him.
And they understood that this was the personality of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
In fact Abu Bakr(ابوبكر), he gave Khutba(خطبه) when he became Khalifah(خليفه).
He says: Sometimes I could get angry.
So, avoid me when you see that happening, because I don't want to harm any one of you.
So it wasn't a temper that was caused by pride.
No, it was a natural makeup of his personality.
Now, when talking about the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم, I want to make sure that I give you the whole picture.
So I'll try to talk about everything as much as possible, according to my limited knowledge,
and I will not hide some things and focus on others for personal reasons. Because depending on your ideology
or your point of view, we could take things from history and hide others.
For example, somebody who's into spirituality could talk about the spirituality of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) and find a lot to talk about.
And then could hide the Jihad(جهاد) of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
And someone who is, who loves Jihad(جهاد) could talk about the later years of Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق)
and Jihad(جهاد) of Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق)
and hide the other side of Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق), the family man, the spiritual man.
When dealing with history, especially with the Sahabah(صحابه)
the best thing is to tell the truth, the whole truth, and nothing but the truth, because it's important
that we have the whole picture and not to be deceived, one way or another. For example,
I was listening on this set of tapes on Muhammadﷺ.
Now, there was one issue of something that happened with Rasool Allah ﷺ, with one of his wives
in the books of Seerah(سيرة), it's usually mentioned in a line or two.
The speaker spoke about that for about 20 minutes.
Following that was the Ghazwa(غزوة) of Bannu Quraidha(بنوقريظه), the battle between Rasool Allah ﷺ
and the Jewish tribe of Bannu Quraidha(بنوقريظه)
which usually takes pages and pages in books of Seerah(سيرة), that speaker covered it, in four minutes.
It's not fair to give two lines about half an hour and a whole Ghazwa(غزوة)
You pretty much wiped it out.
Why? Because of the Battle of Bannu Quraidha(بنوقريظه) is the controversial issue
with orientalist and with the enemies of Islam, it's one of the issues they pick on and attack.
But this is the history of Rasool Allah ﷺ, and we're proud of everything that Rasool Allah ﷺ did, everything
and we're going to speak about everything publicly, and we're not going to hide anything.
There is nothing to hide in the life of Rasool Allah ﷺ, or in the lives of any of the Sahabah(صحابه) of Rasool Ullah
it's all public information, and it should all be told, and nothing hidden.
So we'll try to talk about everything, even the mistakes.
Now, there are some figures in Islamic history like in the generation of Tabaeen(تابعين)
or Tabe'Tabaeen(تابع تابعين), or some of the other scholars that came on. You hear some amazing things like
- A Shaikh(شيخ), who used to pray 1000 Raka'a(ركعة) per night. And you hear about the one
who used to make Khatam(ختم) of Qur'an 10 times a day, and all of these things, so you kind of get the very rosy picture.
And that was possible with these figures because there wasn't a lot of scrutiny on their lives.
I mean, there wasn't any study of Ilm Ar-Rijaal(علم الرجال) when it comes to narrating their stories.
But with the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم because it's a special generation.
That generation gained the attention of thousands of scholars.
So, they studied everything, in there and they reported everything back
I mean At-Tabri(الطبري) he didn't hide anything he wrote about everything that happened,
which he could get his hands over, so did Ibn Kathir(ابن كثير),
so did Ibn Sa'ad(ابن سعد), so did Ibn Hajar(ابن حجر).
Now, you find that in the generation of the Sahabah(صحابه) you don't have these Rosy idealistic images.
You find that the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم, had shortcomings.
They had their low points, they had their disputes,
they even at one point of time, fought with each other.
If you study the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم, and you study everything about them,
you would come to realize that the Sahabah(صحابه) represent the perfection of humanity with all of its shortcomings.
They are the perfect human generation
with all of the shortcomings that come with humanity.
They were human beings, they were not angels,
they were the best, yet as human beings, everyone makes mistakes.
The Ambiyaa(انبياء) of Allahعَزّوجَلّ, Allah made them Maasoomeen(معصومين), Allah made them free of sin
with the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم, they struggled and they did their best, the best that they could.
So we'll try to talk about the whole picture
and not to give you a rosy romantic image that is impractical and not realistic.
And in fact it's detrimental.
Why.?
When we say that the Sahabah(صحابه) are role models for us.
If we make them equal to angels,
then that will be very depressing for us because we will never be able to be like them.
And that will make us lose hope.
It will make us give up but when you see the Sahabah(صحابه), for who they were,
it gives you a hope and makes you try, you keep on trying.
Now, we have to all admit that will never get there we will never be like the lowest of the Sahabah(صحابه).
But at least this will give us hope.
And make us try and it will challenge us.
Now the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم, their lifestyle was difficult.
And Allah سبحانه تعالى put them in very tough tests.
That's why we found among the Sahabah(صحابه), they fought with each other
and they had disputes, it's because of the circumstances.
Somebody who's sitting down doing nothing, is not going to make a mistake.
But the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم had a very, very active life
I mean, when you look at one of the Sahabah(صحابه), and you see,
all of the events that were attributed to such a person and you look at their lifespan, it's a miracle.
How did they do it?
How did they get the chance to fight in Badr(بدر),
Uhud(أحَد), Al-Khandaq(الخندق), Al-Hudaybiyyah(الحديبيه) Fatiha Makkah(فتح مكه),
Mo'ta(مؤته), Tabook(تبوك), they went to Hajj(حج) in Hajja Tul Widah(حجة الوداع).
And then they had time to make to make Ummrah(عمره), to pray Qiyyam Ul Lail(قيام اليل)
to memorize Qur'an and to study with Rasool Allah ﷺ
and to teach and then they became governors, military generals.
And then they had huge families married to 2, 3, 4 wives.
It was the exception among them to find the Sahabi(صحابي) married to one.
They had many children.
They had to run businesses, they had farms.
I mean, when you look at all of the events that was going on in the life of one Sahabi(صحابي),
there was so much going on, in their lives.
But for example, somebody who is comfortably leading a peaceful life, they're not being challenged
they're not going through hardships, they're not tested to the limit, because the battlefield is the greatest test.
And the Sahabah(صحابه) didn't go through that once they went through it many times
and that brings the best and the worst, out of the person.
That is where they knew, where As-Sadiqeen(الصادقين) were and where the Munafiqeen(منافقين) were.
It wasn't in times of peace, they knew it, in the battlefield.
That's where Nifaaq(نفاق) would show up.
Allahعَزّوجَلّ purified that generation.
So that the ones, who were left and were considered among the Sahabah(صحابه) were tested,
they were tested to the limit.
So, Sahabah(صحابه) whom Rasool Allah ﷺ passed away and he was pleased with them - you dont worry about them
because they have been through all the tests.
And whatever happens after that, whether it's happened in the incidence of Al-Jammal(جمل) or between Ali(علي) and Muawiyyah(معاويه),
when it's compared to the scale of their deeds it's irrelevant.